{
  "jesus_quiz_modules": ["Old and New Testaments","Jesus Christ","Jesus’ Christ Advent Prophecies in the Old Testament","Apostles","Patriarchs and Matriarchs","12 Tribes of Israel","Moses","The Exodus","Judges of Israel","Prophets of Israel","Kings of Israel and Judah"],
  "jesus_quiz_list": [
    {
      "Old and New Testaments": [
        {
          "question": "What does “Bible” mean?",
          "option1": "bibliography",
          "option2": "bubble ",
          "option3": "“books” from Greek",
          "answer": "“books” from Greek",
          "full_answer": "The Bible gets its name from a Greek word meaning “books”."
        },
        {
          "question": "The Bible is sacred to",
          "option1": "the Christian religion",
          "option2": "the Jewish religion ",
          "option3": "both",
          "answer": "both",
          "full_answer": "The Bible is sacred to the Christian and Jewish religion."
        },
        {
          "question": "The Old Testament is also called",
          "option1": "the Old Book",
          "option2": "the Hebrew Bible",
          "option3": "the Magic Book",
          "answer": "the Hebrew Bible",
          "full_answer": "The Old Testament is also called the 'HebrewBible'."
        },
        {
          "question": "What are the three parts of the Old Testament?",
          "option1": "The Pentagon, The Prophets, The Writings",
          "option2": "Genesis, Exodus, Leviticus",
          "option3": "The Pentateuch, The Prophets, The Writings",
          "answer": "The Pentateuch, The Prophets, The Writings",
          "full_answer": "The three parts of the Old Testament are The Pentateuch, The Prophets, The Writings."
        },
        {
          "question": "The Pentateuch includes",
          "option1": "four books",
          "option2": "fifteen books",
          "option3": "five books",
          "answer": "five books",
          "full_answer": "The Pentateuch includes five books: Genesis, Exodus, Leviticus, Numbers, Deuteronomy"
        },
        {
          "question": "The Pentateuch is also called",
          "option1": "The Four Books of Jesus",
          "option2": "The Gospel",
          "option3": "The Five Books of Moses",
          "answer": "The Five Books of Moses",
          "full_answer": "The Pentateuch is also called The Five Books of Moses"
        },
        {
          "question": "What does 'Gospel' mean?",
          "option1": "'goodnews' from Greek",
          "option2": "gossip ",
          "option3": "Jesus Christ",
          "answer": "'goodnews' from Greek",
          "full_answer": "Gospel means 'goodnews' from Greek."
        },
        {
          "question": "The Gospel includes",
          "option1": "five books",
          "option2": "one book ",
          "option3": "four books",
          "answer": "four books",
          "full_answer": "The Gospel includes four books: St Matthew, St Mark, St Luke, St John"
        },
        {
          "question": "What does 'testament' mean??",
          "option1": "test",
          "option2": "'covenant' or 'contract'",
          "option3": "taste",
          "answer": "'covenant' or 'contract'",
          "full_answer": "'Testament' means 'covenant' or 'contract'"
        },
        {
          "question": "How many books are included in the Old Testament?",
          "option1": "5",
          "option2": "4 ",
          "option3": "39",
          "answer": "39",
          "full_answer": "There are 39 books included in the Old Testament."
        },
        {
          "question": "'JesusChrist' is mentioned in",
          "option1": "the Old Testament",
          "option2": "the New Testament",
          "option3": "both",
          "answer": "the New Testament",
          "full_answer": "'JesusChrist' is mentioned in the New Testament"
        },
        {
          "question": "How many books are included in the New Testament?",
          "option1": "27",
          "option2": "39 ",
          "option3": "4",
          "answer": "27",
          "full_answer": "There are included 27 books in the New Testament."
        },
        {
          "question": "In what language was the Old Testament written?",
          "option1": "Middle English",
          "option2": "Latin",
          "option3": "mainly in ancient Hebrew",
          "answer": "mainly in ancient Hebrew",
          "full_answer": "The Old Testament was originally almost entirely written in ancient Hebrew, with a few short elements in Aramaic."
        },
        {
          "question": "In what language was the New Testament written?",
          "option1": "probably in Latin",
          "option2": "probably in Greek",
          "option3": "probably in ancient Hebrew",
          "answer": "probably in Greek",
          "full_answer": "Probably in Greek, though some may have been first written in Aramaic"
        },
        {
          "question": "When was the first translation of the Bible made into English?",
          "option1": "1600 A.D. by Shakespeare",
          "option2": "1382 A.D. by John Wycliffe ",
          "option3": "both answers are correct",
          "answer": "1382 A.D. by John Wycliffe",
          "full_answer": "The first translation of the Bible was made into English in 1382 A.D. by John Wycliffe."
        },
        {
          "question": "What is the Gutenberg Bible",
          "option1": "the first book ever printed",
          "option2": "the second book ever printed ",
          "option3": "a fancy Bible",
          "answer": "the first book ever printed",
          "full_answer": "The Gutenberg Bible is the first book ever printed (in 1454 A.D. by Johannes Gutenberg who invented the 'typemold' for the printing press.)"
        }
      ],
      "Jesus Christ": [
        {
          "question": "Jesus was born in",
          "option1": "6 AD",
          "option2": "1000 AD ",
          "option3": "6 BC",
          "answer": "6 BC",
          "full_answer": "Jesus was born in 6 BC"
        },
        {
          "question": "Jesus was born in",
          "option1": "Bethlehem, USA",
          "option2": "Nazareth",
          "option3": "Bethlehem, Judea",
          "answer": "Bethlehem, Judea",
          "full_answer": "Jesus was born in Bethlehem, Judea"
        },
        {
          "question": "Who visited Mary before Jesus Birth",
          "option1": "angel Michael",
          "option2": "angel Gabriel",
          "option3": "angel Raphael",
          "answer": "angel Gabriel",
          "full_answer": "Angel Gabriel visited Mary before Jesus Birth."
        },
        {
          "question": "The infant Christ was visited by the",
          "option1": "Kings",
          "option2": "Angels",
          "option3": "Magi",
          "answer": "Magi",
          "full_answer": "The infant Christ was visited by the Magi."
        },
        {
          "question": "Where did Jesus visit as a boy?",
          "option1": "Solomon Temple",
          "option2": "First Temple",
          "option3": "Second Temple",
          "answer": "Second Temple",
          "full_answer": "Jesus visited the Second Temple as a boy."
        },
        {
          "question": "Jesus was baptized by",
          "option1": "John the Baptist, Jerusalem",
          "option2": "John the Baptist, Jordan River",
          "option3": "Judas Iscariot, Jordan River",
          "answer": "John the Baptist, Jordan River",
          "full_answer": "Jesus was baptized by John the Baptist, Jordan River."
        },
        {
          "question": "What does 'Gospel' mean?",
          "option1": "'goodnews' from Greek",
          "option2": "gossip ",
          "option3": "Jesus Christ",
          "answer": "'goodnews' from Greek",
          "full_answer": "Gospel means 'goodnews' from Greek."
        },
        {
          "question": "The Gospel includes",
          "option1": "five books",
          "option2": "one book ",
          "option3": "four books",
          "answer": "four books",
          "full_answer": "The Gospel includes four books: St Matthew, St Mark, St Luke, St John"
        },
        {
          "question": "'Christ' means",
          "option1": "in English Jesus, in Greek Messiah",
          "option2": "in English the anointed one, in Hebrew Messiah",
          "option3": "in English Baptist in Greek Christianity",
          "answer": "in English the anointed one, in Hebrew Messiah",
          "full_answer": "'Christ' means in English the anointed one, in Hebrew Messiah."
        },
        {
          "question": "Jesus first miracle was",
          "option1": "raising the dead",
          "option2": "healing the sick ",
          "option3": "turning water into wine",
          "answer": "turning water into wine",
          "full_answer": "Jesus first miracle was turning water into wine."
        },
        {
          "question": "How many apostles did Jesus nomiante?",
          "option1": "12",
          "option2": "7",
          "option3": "11",
          "answer": "12",
          "full_answer": "Jesus nominated 12 apostles."
        },
        {
          "question": "Jesus was betrayed by",
          "option1": "Jude",
          "option2": "Judas Iscariot ",
          "option3": "the Gospel of Judas",
          "answer": "Judas Iscariot",
          "full_answer": "Jesus was betrayed by Judas Iscariot."
        },
        {
          "question": "Jesus was executed on the orders of",
          "option1": "The Jews",
          "option2": "Pontius Pilate",
          "option3": "The Crusaders",
          "answer": "Pontius Pilate",
          "full_answer": "Jesus was executed on the orders of Pontius Pilate."
        },
        {
          "question": "Jesus Christ was crucified in",
          "option1": "1 AD",
          "option2": "30 AD",
          "option3": "6 BC",
          "answer": "30 AD",
          "full_answer": "Jesus Christ was crucified in 30 AD."
        },
        {
          "question": "After his resurrection, Jesus first appeared to",
          "option1": "Mary Magdalene",
          "option2": "Virgin Mary",
          "option3": "Paul of Tarsus",
          "answer": "Mary Magdalene",
          "full_answer": "After his resurrection, Jesus first appeared to Mary Magdalene."
        },
        {
          "question": "What is the Gutenberg Bible",
          "option1": "the first book ever printed",
          "option2": "the second book ever printed ",
          "option3": "a fancy Bible",
          "answer": "the first book ever printed",
          "full_answer": "The Gutenberg Bible is the first book ever printed (in 1454 A.D. by Johannes Gutenberg who invented the 'typemold' for the printing press.)"
        }
      ],
      "Jesus’ Christ Advent Prophecies in the Old Testament": [
        {
          "question": "For to us a child is born...and the government will be on his shoulders...He will reign on David`s throne and over his kingdom... (9:6-7)",
          "option1": "Micah",
          "option2": "Jeremiah ",
          "option3": "Isaiah",
          "answer": "Isaiah",
          "full_answer": "Isaiah 9:6-7"
        },
        {
          "question": "But you, Bethlehem Ephrathah, though you are small among the clans of Judah, out of you will come for me one who will be ruler over Israel, whose origins are from of old, from ancient times. (5:2)",
          "option1": "Samuel",
          "option2": "Ezekiel",
          "option3": "Micah",
          "answer": "Micah",
          "full_answer": "Micah 5:2"
        },
        {
          "question": "Behold, the days come, saith the LORD, that I will make a new covenant with the house of Israel, and with the house of Judah. (31:31)",
          "option1": "Amos",
          "option2": "Jeremiah",
          "option3": "Habakkuk",
          "answer": "Jeremiah",
          "full_answer": "Jeremiah 31:31"
        },
        {
          "question": "Hear you now, O house of David... Therefore the LORD himself shall give you a sign; A virgin shall conceive, and bear a son, and shall call his name Immanuel. (7:13-14)",
          "option1": "Jeremiah",
          "option2": "Zephaniah",
          "option3": "Isaiah",
          "answer": "Isaiah",
          "full_answer": " Isaiah 7:13-14"
        },
        {
          "question": "All we like sheep have gone astray; we have turned every one to his own way; and the LORD hath laid on him the iniquity of us all. (53:6)",
          "option1": "Jeremiah",
          "option2": "Malachi",
          "option3": "Isaiah",
          "answer": "Isaiah",
          "full_answer": "Isaiah 53:6"
        },
        {
          "question": "For it is not an enemy who reproaches me...But it is you, a man my equal, my companion and my familiar friend. (55:12-14)",
          "option1": "Zechariah",
          "option2": "Psalms",
          "option3": "Zephaniah",
          "answer": "Psalms",
          "full_answer": "Psalms 55:12-14"
        },
        {
          "question": "Then the LORD said to me, “Throw it to the potter, that magnificent price at which I was valued by them.” So I took the thirty shekels of silver and threw them to the potter in the house of the LORD (11:13)",
          "option1": "'Zechariah",
          "option2": "Micah ",
          "option3": "Ezekiel",
          "answer": "Zechariah",
          "full_answer": "Zechariah 11:13"
        },
        {
          "question": "I gave My back to those who strike Me, And My cheeks to those who pluck out the beard; I did not cover My face from humiliation and spitting. (50:6 I)",
          "option1": "Daniel",
          "option2": "Haggai",
          "option3": "Isaiah",
          "answer": "Isaiah",
          "full_answer": "Isaiah 50:61"
        },
        {
          "question": "For dogs have surrounded me; A band of evildoers has encompassed me; They pierced my hands and my feet. (22:16)",
          "option1": "Joel",
          "option2": "Psalms",
          "option3": "Daniel",
          "answer": "Psalms",
          "full_answer": "Psalms 22:16"
        },
        {
          "question": "Commit yourself to the LORD; let Him deliver him; Let Him rescue him, because He delights in him ( 22:8)",
          "option1": "Jeremiah",
          "option2": "Ezekiel ",
          "option3": "Psalms",
          "answer": "Psalms",
          "full_answer": "Psalms 22:8"
        },
        {
          "question": "And I will pour out on the house of David and on the inhabitants of Jerusalem, the Spirit of grace and of supplication, so that they will look on Me whom they have pierced; and they will mourn for Him, as one mourns for an only son, and they will weep bitterly over Him, like the bitter weeping over a first-born (12:10)",
          "option1": "Jeremiah",
          "option2": "Zechariah",
          "option3": "Daniel",
          "answer": "Zechariah",
          "full_answer": "Zechariah 12:10"
        },
        {
          "question": "And it will come about in that day, declares the Lord GOD, That I shall make the sun go down at noon And make the earth dark in broad daylight. (8:9)",
          "option1": "Amos",
          "option2": "Haggai ",
          "option3": "Malachi",
          "answer": "Amos",
          "full_answer": "Amos 8:9"
        },
        {
          "question": "I am poured out like water, And all my bones are out of joint; My heart is like wax; It is melted within me. (22:14)",
          "option1": "Baruch",
          "option2": "Psalms",
          "option3": "Nahum",
          "answer": "Psalms",
          "full_answer": "Psalms 22:14"
        },
        {
          "question": "When Israel was a child, I loved him, and out of Egypt I called my son. (11:1)",
          "option1": "Isaiah",
          "option2": "Hosea",
          "option3": "Psalms",
          "answer": "Hosea",
          "full_answer": "Hosea 11:1"
        },
        {
          "question": "He was oppressed and afflicted, yet he did not open his mouth; he was led like a lamb to the slaughter, and as a sheep before her shearers is silent, so he did not open his mouth. (53:7)",
          "option1": "Haggai",
          "option2": "Isaiah",
          "option3": "Psalms",
          "answer": "Isaiah",
          "full_answer": "Isaiah 53:7"
        },
        {
          "question": "After two days will he revive us: in the third day he will raise us up, and we shall live in his sight (6:2)",
          "option1": "Hosea",
          "option2": "Micah",
          "option3": "Jeremiah",
          "answer": "Hosea",
          "full_answer": "Hosea 6:2"
        }
      ],
      "Apostles": [
        {
          "question": "Apostle means in Greek",
          "option1": "envoy",
          "option2": "messenger ",
          "option3": "both",
          "answer": "both",
          "full_answer": "Apostle in Greek: someone sent forth, envoy, messenger."
        },
        {
          "question": "Which apostle was nicknamed 'rock' by Jesus?",
          "option1": "James",
          "option2": "Thomas",
          "option3": "Peter",
          "answer": "Peter",
          "full_answer": "Apostle Peter was nicknamed 'rock' by Jesus."
        },
        {
          "question": "Which apostle was the brother of Peter",
          "option1": "John",
          "option2": "Andrew",
          "option3": "Philip",
          "answer": "Andrew",
          "full_answer": "Andrew was the brother of Peter."
        },
        {
          "question": "Which apostles were the sons of Zebedee?",
          "option1": "Matthew and Thomas",
          "option2": "Simon and Jude",
          "option3": "James and John",
          "answer": "James and John",
          "full_answer": "James and John were the sons of Zebedee."
        },
        {
          "question": "Philip came from",
          "option1": "Jerusalem",
          "option2": "Capernaum",
          "option3": "Bethsaida",
          "answer": "Bethsaida",
          "full_answer": "Philip came from Bethsaida."
        },
        {
          "question": "Many apostles were",
          "option1": "bakers",
          "option2": "fishermen",
          "option3": "blacksmiths",
          "answer": "fishermen",
          "full_answer": "Many apostles were fishermen."
        },
        {
          "question": "What does 'Gospel' mean?",
          "option1": "'goodnews' from Greek",
          "option2": "gossip ",
          "option3": "Jesus Christ",
          "answer": "'goodnews' from Greek",
          "full_answer": "Gospel means 'goodnews' from Greek."
        },
        {
          "question": "The Gospel includes",
          "option1": "five books",
          "option2": "one book ",
          "option3": "four books",
          "answer": "four books",
          "full_answer": "The Gospel includes four books: St Matthew, St Mark, St Luke, St John"
        },
        {
          "question": "Which apostle is sometimes called Nathanael?",
          "option1": "Simon",
          "option2": "Bartholomew",
          "option3": "Judas Iscariot",
          "answer": "Bartholomew",
          "full_answer": "Bartholomew is sometimes called Nathanael."
        },
        {
          "question": "Matthew was",
          "option1": "a blacksmith from Jerusalem",
          "option2": "a fishermen from Bethsaida ",
          "option3": "a tax collector from Capernaum",
          "answer": "a tax collector from Capernaum",
          "full_answer": "Matthew was a tax collector from Capernaum."
        },
        {
          "question": "Which apostle doubted the resurrection of Jesus?",
          "option1": "Pole",
          "option2": "Thomas ",
          "option3": "both",
          "answer": "Thomas",
          "full_answer": "Thomas doubted the resurrection of Jesus."
        },
        {
          "question": "How many apostles did Jesus nomiante?",
          "option1": "12",
          "option2": "7 ",
          "option3": "11",
          "answer": "12",
          "full_answer": "Jesus nominated 12 apostles."
        },
        {
          "question": "Jesus was betrayed by",
          "option1": "Jude",
          "option2": "Judas Iscariot",
          "option3": "the Gospel of Judas",
          "answer": "Judas Iscariot",
          "full_answer": "Jesus was betrayed by Judas Iscariot."
        },
        {
          "question": "Who was chosen to replace Judas Iscariot?",
          "option1": "Jude",
          "option2": "Matthias",
          "option3": "James",
          "answer": "Matthias",
          "full_answer": "Matthias was chosen to replace Judas Iscariot."
        },
        {
          "question": "Was Paul one of the Twelve nominated by Jesus?",
          "option1": "yes",
          "option2": "no",
          "option3": "it depends",
          "answer": "no",
          "full_answer": "Paul was not one of the Twelve, though many times considered in Christianity as an Apostle."
        },
        {
          "question": "Who are most prominent figures, after Jesus, in infant Christianity?",
          "option1": "Apostle Peter, Paul of Tarsus",
          "option2": "James, Judas Iscariot",
          "option3": "Peter, Paul and Mary",
          "answer": "Apostle Peter, Paul of Tarsus",
          "full_answer": "Apostle Peter and Paul of Tarsus are most prominent figures, after Jesus, in infant Christianity."
        }
      ],
      "Patriarchs and Matriarchs": [
        {
          "question": "There are",
          "option1": "1 Patriarch and 1 Matriarch",
          "option2": "4 Patriarchs and 3 Matriarchs ",
          "option3": "3 Patriarchs and 4 Matriarchs",
          "answer": "3 Patriarchs and 4 Matriarchs",
          "full_answer": "There are 3 Patriarchs and 4 Matriarchs."
        },
        {
          "question": "The 3 Patriarchs are",
          "option1": "Jesus, John the Baptist and Virgin Mary",
          "option2": "Jesus, Abraham and Muhammad",
          "option3": "Abraham, Isaac and Jacob",
          "answer": "Abraham, Isaac and Jacob",
          "full_answer": "The 3 Patriarchs are Abraham, Isaac and Jacob."
        },
        {
          "question": "The 4 Matriarchs are",
          "option1": "Virgin Mary, Mary Magdalene, Mary Tudor",
          "option2": "Sarah, Rebecca, Leah and Rachel",
          "option3": "Sarah, Rebecca, Leah and Mary",
          "answer": "Sarah, Rebecca, Leah and Rachel",
          "full_answer": "The 4 Matriarchs are Sarah, Rebecca, Leah and Rachel."
        },
        {
          "question": "Sarah is the wife of",
          "option1": "Isaac",
          "option2": "Jacob",
          "option3": "Abraham",
          "answer": "Abraham",
          "full_answer": "Sarah is the wife of Abraham."
        },
        {
          "question": "Rebecca is the mother of",
          "option1": "Isaac and Jacob",
          "option2": "did not have children",
          "option3": "Esau and Jacob",
          "answer": "Esau and Jacob",
          "full_answer": "Rebecca is the mother of Esau and Jacob."
        },
        {
          "question": "Leah and Rachel are",
          "option1": "friends and wives of Jacob",
          "option2": "sisters and wives of Jacob",
          "option3": "daughters of Isaac",
          "answer": "sisters and wives of Jacob",
          "full_answer": "Leah and Rachel are sisters and the wives of Jacob."
        },
        {
          "question": "Hagar is",
          "option1": "the wife of Abraham and mother of Ishmael",
          "option2": "the handmaid of Sarah ",
          "option3": "both",
          "answer": "both",
          "full_answer": "Hagar is the wife of Abraham, mother of Ishmael and handmaid of Sarah."
        },
        {
          "question": "Abraham`s father is",
          "option1": "Noah",
          "option2": "Adam",
          "option3": "Terah",
          "answer": "Terah",
          "full_answer": "Abraham`s father is Terah."
        },
        {
          "question": "Where was Abraham commanded by God to offer his son, Isaac, up as a sacrifice?",
          "option1": "Mount Sinai",
          "option2": "Mount Moriah",
          "option3": "both",
          "answer": "Mount Moriah",
          "full_answer": "Abraham was commanded by God to offer his son, Isaac, up as a sacrifice on Mount Moriah.'"
        },
        {
          "question": "Which Patriarch was also called Israel?",
          "option1": "Abraham",
          "option2": "Isaac",
          "option3": "Jacob",
          "answer": "Jacob",
          "full_answer": "Jacob was also called Israel."
        },
        {
          "question": "Which are the Abrahamic Religions?",
          "option1": "Judaism and Christianity",
          "option2": "Judaism, Christianity and Islam",
          "option3": "Islam",
          "answer": "Judaism, Christianity and Islam",
          "full_answer": "Judaism, Christianity and Islam are the Abrahamic religions."
        },
        {
          "question": "How old were Abraham and Sarah when they gave birth to Isaac?",
          "option1": "Abraham 100, Sarah 90",
          "option2": "Abraham 1000, Sarah 900 ",
          "option3": "Abraham 59, Sarah 32",
          "answer": "Abraham 100, Sarah 90",
          "full_answer": "When they gave birth to Isaac, Abraham was 100 years old and Sarah 90."
        },
        {
          "question": "Who were twins?",
          "option1": "Rachel and Leah",
          "option2": "Jacob and Esau",
          "option3": "Hagar and Sarah",
          "answer": "Jacob and Esau",
          "full_answer": " Jacob and Esau were twins."
        },
        {
          "question": "Where was Abraham born?",
          "option1": "Jerusalem, Canaan",
          "option2": "Ur, Chaldea",
          "option3": "Giza, Egypt",
          "answer": "Ur, Chaldea",
          "full_answer": "Abraham and his family were originally from the city of Ur, Chaldea"
        },
        {
          "question": "How many children did Jacob have?",
          "option1": "12",
          "option2": "13",
          "option3": "he did not have children",
          "answer": "13",
          "full_answer": "Jacob had 13 children (12 sons, the tribes of Israel and 1 daughter, Dina)."
        },
        {
          "question": "Where is located The Cave of the Patriarchs?",
          "option1": "Hebron",
          "option2": "Jerusalem",
          "option3": "Bethlehem",
          "answer": "Hebron",
          "full_answer": "The Cave of the Patriarchs is located in the ancient city of Hebron"
        }
      ],
      "12 Tribes of Israel": [
        {
          "question": "Who is the firstborn son of Jacob?",
          "option1": "Simeon",
          "option2": "Judah ",
          "option3": "Reuben",
          "answer": "Reuben",
          "full_answer": "Reuben is the firstborn son of Jacob."
        },
        {
          "question": "Who is the twelfth (last) son of Jacob?",
          "option1": "Joseph",
          "option2": "Asher",
          "option3": "Benjamin",
          "answer": "Benjamin",
          "full_answer": "Benjamin is the twelfth son of Jacob."
        },
        {
          "question": "Who fathered the Ephraim and Manasseh tribes?",
          "option1": "Jacob",
          "option2": "Joseph",
          "option3": "Judah",
          "answer": "Joseph",
          "full_answer": "Joseph fathered the Ephraim and Manasseh tribes."
        },
        {
          "question": "Who was sold into slavery?",
          "option1": "Dan",
          "option2": "Gad",
          "option3": "Joseph",
          "answer": "Joseph",
          "full_answer": "Joseph was sold into slavery?"
        },
        {
          "question": "King David and Jesus were from the tribe of",
          "option1": "Ephraim",
          "option2": "Joseph",
          "option3": "Judah",
          "answer": "Judah",
          "full_answer": "King David and Jesus were from the tribe of Judah."
        },
        {
          "question": "Which tribe was blessed by Jacob: 'he will provide the king`s delights.'",
          "option1": "Dan",
          "option2": "Asher",
          "option3": "Naphtali",
          "answer": "Asher",
          "full_answer": "Asher was blessed by Jacob: 'he will provide the king`s delights'."
        },
        {
          "question": "Which tribe is described as still residing in ships?",
          "option1": "Dan",
          "option2": "Issachar ",
          "option3": "Levi",
          "answer": "Dan",
          "full_answer": "Dan is described as still residing in ships."
        },
        {
          "question": "The mother of Gad was",
          "option1": "Bilhah",
          "option2": "Leah",
          "option3": "Zilpah",
          "answer": "Zilpah",
          "full_answer": "The mother of Gad was Zilpah."
        },
        {
          "question": "According to Jewish tradition the descendants of Issachar are",
          "option1": "warriors",
          "option2": "men of learning",
          "option3": "fishermen",
          "answer": "men of learning",
          "full_answer": "According to Jewish tradition the descendants of Issachar are men of learning."
        },
        {
          "question": "Samson is from the tribe of",
          "option1": "Benjamin",
          "option2": "Judah ",
          "option3": "Dan",
          "answer": "Dan",
          "full_answer": "Samson is from the tribe of Dan."
        },
        {
          "question": "Which tribe was distinguished as servant to God and thus was not allocated any territory?",
          "option1": "Zebulun",
          "option2": "Levi",
          "option3": "Reuben",
          "answer": "Levi",
          "full_answer": "Levi tribe was distinguished as servant to God and thus was not allocated any territory."
        },
        {
          "question": "Which tribe were described as brave soldiers in the Song of Deborah?",
          "option1": "Naphtali",
          "option2": "Judah ",
          "option3": "Dan",
          "answer": "Naphtali",
          "full_answer": "The Naphtali tribe were described as brave soldiers in the Song of Deborah."
        },
        {
          "question": "Who stayed behind as collateral for Benjamin so that his brothers would return from Canaan to Egypt?",
          "option1": "Joseph",
          "option2": "Simeon",
          "option3": "Jacob",
          "answer": "Simeon",
          "full_answer": "Simeon stayed behind as collateral for Benjamin so that his brothers would return from Canaan to Egypt."
        },
        {
          "question": "To whom refers: 'he will be a harbour for ships'?",
          "option1": "Dan",
          "option2": "Zebulun",
          "option3": "Naphtali",
          "answer": "Zebulun",
          "full_answer": "To Zebulun refers: 'he will be a harbour for ships'."
        },
        {
          "question": "Who were brothers?",
          "option1": "Rachel and Leah",
          "option2": "Ephraim and Manasseh",
          "option3": "Jacob and Isaac",
          "answer": "Ephraim and Manasseh",
          "full_answer": "Ephraim and Manasseh were brothers."
        },
        {
          "question": "Moses is from the tribe of",
          "option1": "Levi",
          "option2": "Judah",
          "option3": "Joseph",
          "answer": "Levi",
          "full_answer": "Moses is from the tribe of Levi."
        }
      ],
      "Moses": [
        {
          "question": "What does “Bible” mean?",
          "option1": "bibliography",
          "option2": "bubble ",
          "option3": "“books” from Greek",
          "answer": "“books” from Greek",
          "full_answer": "The Bible gets its name from a Greek word meaning “books”."
        },
        {
          "question": "The Bible is sacred to",
          "option1": "the Christian religion",
          "option2": "the Jewish religion ",
          "option3": "both",
          "answer": "both",
          "full_answer": "The Bible is sacred to the Christian and Jewish religion."
        },
        {
          "question": "The Old Testament is also called",
          "option1": "the Old Book",
          "option2": "the Hebrew Bible",
          "option3": "the Magic Book",
          "answer": "the Hebrew Bible",
          "full_answer": "The Old Testament is also called the 'HebrewBible'."
        },
        {
          "question": "What are the three parts of the Old Testament?",
          "option1": "The Pentagon, The Prophets, The Writings",
          "option2": "Genesis, Exodus, Leviticus",
          "option3": "The Pentateuch, The Prophets, The Writings",
          "answer": "The Pentateuch, The Prophets, The Writings",
          "full_answer": "The three parts of the Old Testament are The Pentateuch, The Prophets, The Writings."
        },
        {
          "question": "The Pentateuch includes",
          "option1": "four books",
          "option2": "fifteen books",
          "option3": "five books",
          "answer": "five books",
          "full_answer": "The Pentateuch includes five books: Genesis, Exodus, Leviticus, Numbers, Deuteronomy"
        },
        {
          "question": "The Pentateuch is also called",
          "option1": "The Four Books of Jesus",
          "option2": "The Gospel",
          "option3": "“books” from Greek",
          "answer": "The Five Books of Moses",
          "full_answer": "The Pentateuch is also called The Five Books of Moses"
        },
        {
          "question": "What does 'Gospel' mean?",
          "option1": "'goodnews' from Greek",
          "option2": "gossip ",
          "option3": "Jesus Christ",
          "answer": "'goodnews' from Greek",
          "full_answer": "Gospel means 'goodnews' from Greek."
        },
        {
          "question": "The Gospel includes",
          "option1": "five books",
          "option2": "one book ",
          "option3": "four books",
          "answer": "four books",
          "full_answer": "The Gospel includes four books: St Matthew, St Mark, St Luke, St John"
        },
        {
          "question": "What does 'testament' mean??",
          "option1": "test",
          "option2": "'covenant' or 'contract'",
          "option3": "taste",
          "answer": "'covenant' or 'contract'",
          "full_answer": "'Testament' means 'covenant' or 'contract'"
        },
        {
          "question": "How many books are included in the Old Testament?",
          "option1": "5",
          "option2": "4 ",
          "option3": "39",
          "answer": "39",
          "full_answer": "There are 39 books included in the Old Testament."
        },
        {
          "question": "'JesusChrist' is mentioned in",
          "option1": "the Old Testament",
          "option2": "the New Testament ",
          "option3": "both",
          "answer": "the New Testament",
          "full_answer": "'JesusChrist' is mentioned in the New Testament"
        },
        {
          "question": "How many books are included in the New Testament?",
          "option1": "27",
          "option2": "39 ",
          "option3": "4",
          "answer": "27",
          "full_answer": "There are included 27 books in the New Testament."
        },
        {
          "question": "In what language was the Old Testament written?",
          "option1": "Middle English",
          "option2": "Latin",
          "option3": "mainly in ancient Hebrew",
          "answer": "mainly in ancient Hebrew",
          "full_answer": "The Old Testament was originally almost entirely written in ancient Hebrew, with a few short elements in Aramaic."
        },
        {
          "question": "In what language was the New Testament written?",
          "option1": "probably in Latin",
          "option2": "probably in Greek ",
          "option3": "probably in ancient Hebrew",
          "answer": "probably in Greek",
          "full_answer": "Probably in Greek, though some may have been first written in Aramaic"
        },
        {
          "question": "When was the first translation of the Bible made into English?",
          "option1": "1600 A.D. by Shakespeare",
          "option2": "1382 A.D. by John Wycliffe ",
          "option3": "both answers are correct",
          "answer": "1382 A.D. by John Wycliffe",
          "full_answer": "The first translation of the Bible was made into English in 1382 A.D. by John Wycliffe."
        },
        {
          "question": "What is the Gutenberg Bible",
          "option1": "the first book ever printed",
          "option2": "the second book ever printed ",
          "option3": "a fancy Bible",
          "answer": "the first book ever printed",
          "full_answer": "The Gutenberg Bible is the first book ever printed (in 1454 A.D. by Johannes Gutenberg who invented the 'typemold' for the printing press.)"
        }
      ],
      "The Exodus": [
        {
          "question": "What does “Bible” mean?",
          "option1": "bibliography",
          "option2": "bubble ",
          "option3": "“books” from Greek",
          "answer": "“books” from Greek",
          "full_answer": "The Bible gets its name from a Greek word meaning “books”."
        },
        {
          "question": "The Bible is sacred to",
          "option1": "the Christian religion",
          "option2": "the Jewish religion ",
          "option3": "both",
          "answer": "both",
          "full_answer": "The Bible is sacred to the Christian and Jewish religion."
        },
        {
          "question": "The Old Testament is also called",
          "option1": "the Old Book",
          "option2": "the Hebrew Bible",
          "option3": "the Magic Book",
          "answer": "the Hebrew Bible",
          "full_answer": "The Old Testament is also called the 'HebrewBible'."
        },
        {
          "question": "What are the three parts of the Old Testament?",
          "option1": "The Pentagon, The Prophets, The Writings",
          "option2": "Genesis, Exodus, Leviticus",
          "option3": "The Pentateuch, The Prophets, The Writings",
          "answer": "The Pentateuch, The Prophets, The Writings",
          "full_answer": "The three parts of the Old Testament are The Pentateuch, The Prophets, The Writings."
        },
        {
          "question": "The Pentateuch includes",
          "option1": "four books",
          "option2": "fifteen books",
          "option3": "five books",
          "answer": "five books",
          "full_answer": "The Pentateuch includes five books: Genesis, Exodus, Leviticus, Numbers, Deuteronomy"
        },
        {
          "question": "The Pentateuch is also called",
          "option1": "The Four Books of Jesus",
          "option2": "The Gospel",
          "option3": "“books” from Greek",
          "answer": "The Five Books of Moses",
          "full_answer": "The Pentateuch is also called The Five Books of Moses"
        },
        {
          "question": "What does 'Gospel' mean?",
          "option1": "'goodnews' from Greek",
          "option2": "gossip ",
          "option3": "Jesus Christ",
          "answer": "'goodnews' from Greek",
          "full_answer": "Gospel means 'goodnews' from Greek."
        },
        {
          "question": "The Gospel includes",
          "option1": "five books",
          "option2": "one book ",
          "option3": "four books",
          "answer": "four books",
          "full_answer": "The Gospel includes four books: St Matthew, St Mark, St Luke, St John"
        },
        {
          "question": "What does 'testament' mean??",
          "option1": "test",
          "option2": "'covenant' or 'contract'",
          "option3": "taste",
          "answer": "'covenant' or 'contract'",
          "full_answer": "'Testament' means 'covenant' or 'contract'"
        },
        {
          "question": "How many books are included in the Old Testament?",
          "option1": "5",
          "option2": "4 ",
          "option3": "39",
          "answer": "39",
          "full_answer": "There are 39 books included in the Old Testament."
        },
        {
          "question": "'JesusChrist' is mentioned in",
          "option1": "the Old Testament",
          "option2": "the New Testament ",
          "option3": "both",
          "answer": "the New Testament",
          "full_answer": "'JesusChrist' is mentioned in the New Testament"
        },
        {
          "question": "How many books are included in the New Testament?",
          "option1": "27",
          "option2": "39 ",
          "option3": "4",
          "answer": "27",
          "full_answer": "There are included 27 books in the New Testament."
        },
        {
          "question": "In what language was the Old Testament written?",
          "option1": "Middle English",
          "option2": "Latin",
          "option3": "mainly in ancient Hebrew",
          "answer": "mainly in ancient Hebrew",
          "full_answer": "The Old Testament was originally almost entirely written in ancient Hebrew, with a few short elements in Aramaic."
        },
        {
          "question": "In what language was the New Testament written?",
          "option1": "probably in Latin",
          "option2": "probably in Greek ",
          "option3": "probably in ancient Hebrew",
          "answer": "probably in Greek",
          "full_answer": "Probably in Greek, though some may have been first written in Aramaic"
        },
        {
          "question": "When was the first translation of the Bible made into English?",
          "option1": "1600 A.D. by Shakespeare",
          "option2": "1382 A.D. by John Wycliffe ",
          "option3": "both answers are correct",
          "answer": "1382 A.D. by John Wycliffe",
          "full_answer": "The first translation of the Bible was made into English in 1382 A.D. by John Wycliffe."
        },
        {
          "question": "What is the Gutenberg Bible",
          "option1": "the first book ever printed",
          "option2": "the second book ever printed ",
          "option3": "a fancy Bible",
          "answer": "the first book ever printed",
          "full_answer": "The Gutenberg Bible is the first book ever printed (in 1454 A.D. by Johannes Gutenberg who invented the 'typemold' for the printing press.)"
        }
      ],
      "Judges of Israel": [
        {
          "question": "What does “Bible” mean?",
          "option1": "bibliography",
          "option2": "bubble ",
          "option3": "“books” from Greek",
          "answer": "“books” from Greek",
          "full_answer": "The Bible gets its name from a Greek word meaning “books”."
        },
        {
          "question": "The Bible is sacred to",
          "option1": "the Christian religion",
          "option2": "the Jewish religion ",
          "option3": "both",
          "answer": "both",
          "full_answer": "The Bible is sacred to the Christian and Jewish religion."
        },
        {
          "question": "The Old Testament is also called",
          "option1": "the Old Book",
          "option2": "the Hebrew Bible",
          "option3": "the Magic Book",
          "answer": "the Hebrew Bible",
          "full_answer": "The Old Testament is also called the 'HebrewBible'."
        },
        {
          "question": "What are the three parts of the Old Testament?",
          "option1": "The Pentagon, The Prophets, The Writings",
          "option2": "Genesis, Exodus, Leviticus",
          "option3": "The Pentateuch, The Prophets, The Writings",
          "answer": "The Pentateuch, The Prophets, The Writings",
          "full_answer": "The three parts of the Old Testament are The Pentateuch, The Prophets, The Writings."
        },
        {
          "question": "The Pentateuch includes",
          "option1": "four books",
          "option2": "fifteen books",
          "option3": "five books",
          "answer": "five books",
          "full_answer": "The Pentateuch includes five books: Genesis, Exodus, Leviticus, Numbers, Deuteronomy"
        },
        {
          "question": "The Pentateuch is also called",
          "option1": "The Four Books of Jesus",
          "option2": "The Gospel",
          "option3": "“books” from Greek",
          "answer": "The Five Books of Moses",
          "full_answer": "The Pentateuch is also called The Five Books of Moses"
        },
        {
          "question": "What does 'Gospel' mean?",
          "option1": "'goodnews' from Greek",
          "option2": "gossip ",
          "option3": "Jesus Christ",
          "answer": "'goodnews' from Greek",
          "full_answer": "Gospel means 'goodnews' from Greek."
        },
        {
          "question": "The Gospel includes",
          "option1": "five books",
          "option2": "one book ",
          "option3": "four books",
          "answer": "four books",
          "full_answer": "The Gospel includes four books: St Matthew, St Mark, St Luke, St John"
        },
        {
          "question": "What does 'testament' mean??",
          "option1": "test",
          "option2": "'covenant' or 'contract'",
          "option3": "taste",
          "answer": "'covenant' or 'contract'",
          "full_answer": "'Testament' means 'covenant' or 'contract'"
        },
        {
          "question": "How many books are included in the Old Testament?",
          "option1": "5",
          "option2": "4 ",
          "option3": "39",
          "answer": "39",
          "full_answer": "There are 39 books included in the Old Testament."
        },
        {
          "question": "'JesusChrist' is mentioned in",
          "option1": "the Old Testament",
          "option2": "the New Testament ",
          "option3": "both",
          "answer": "the New Testament",
          "full_answer": "'JesusChrist' is mentioned in the New Testament"
        },
        {
          "question": "How many books are included in the New Testament?",
          "option1": "27",
          "option2": "39 ",
          "option3": "4",
          "answer": "27",
          "full_answer": "There are included 27 books in the New Testament."
        },
        {
          "question": "In what language was the Old Testament written?",
          "option1": "Middle English",
          "option2": "Latin",
          "option3": "mainly in ancient Hebrew",
          "answer": "mainly in ancient Hebrew",
          "full_answer": "The Old Testament was originally almost entirely written in ancient Hebrew, with a few short elements in Aramaic."
        },
        {
          "question": "In what language was the New Testament written?",
          "option1": "probably in Latin",
          "option2": "probably in Greek ",
          "option3": "probably in ancient Hebrew",
          "answer": "probably in Greek",
          "full_answer": "Probably in Greek, though some may have been first written in Aramaic"
        },
        {
          "question": "When was the first translation of the Bible made into English?",
          "option1": "1600 A.D. by Shakespeare",
          "option2": "1382 A.D. by John Wycliffe ",
          "option3": "both answers are correct",
          "answer": "1382 A.D. by John Wycliffe",
          "full_answer": "The first translation of the Bible was made into English in 1382 A.D. by John Wycliffe."
        },
        {
          "question": "What is the Gutenberg Bible",
          "option1": "the first book ever printed",
          "option2": "the second book ever printed ",
          "option3": "a fancy Bible",
          "answer": "the first book ever printed",
          "full_answer": "The Gutenberg Bible is the first book ever printed (in 1454 A.D. by Johannes Gutenberg who invented the 'typemold' for the printing press.)"
        }
      ],
      "Prophets of Israel": [
        {
          "question": "What does “Bible” mean?",
          "option1": "bibliography",
          "option2": "bubble ",
          "option3": "“books” from Greek",
          "answer": "“books” from Greek",
          "full_answer": "The Bible gets its name from a Greek word meaning “books”."
        },
        {
          "question": "The Bible is sacred to",
          "option1": "the Christian religion",
          "option2": "the Jewish religion ",
          "option3": "both",
          "answer": "both",
          "full_answer": "The Bible is sacred to the Christian and Jewish religion."
        },
        {
          "question": "The Old Testament is also called",
          "option1": "the Old Book",
          "option2": "the Hebrew Bible",
          "option3": "the Magic Book",
          "answer": "the Hebrew Bible",
          "full_answer": "The Old Testament is also called the 'HebrewBible'."
        },
        {
          "question": "What are the three parts of the Old Testament?",
          "option1": "The Pentagon, The Prophets, The Writings",
          "option2": "Genesis, Exodus, Leviticus",
          "option3": "The Pentateuch, The Prophets, The Writings",
          "answer": "The Pentateuch, The Prophets, The Writings",
          "full_answer": "The three parts of the Old Testament are The Pentateuch, The Prophets, The Writings."
        },
        {
          "question": "The Pentateuch includes",
          "option1": "four books",
          "option2": "fifteen books",
          "option3": "five books",
          "answer": "five books",
          "full_answer": "The Pentateuch includes five books: Genesis, Exodus, Leviticus, Numbers, Deuteronomy"
        },
        {
          "question": "The Pentateuch is also called",
          "option1": "The Four Books of Jesus",
          "option2": "The Gospel",
          "option3": "“books” from Greek",
          "answer": "The Five Books of Moses",
          "full_answer": "The Pentateuch is also called The Five Books of Moses"
        },
        {
          "question": "What does 'Gospel' mean?",
          "option1": "'goodnews' from Greek",
          "option2": "gossip ",
          "option3": "Jesus Christ",
          "answer": "'goodnews' from Greek",
          "full_answer": "Gospel means 'goodnews' from Greek."
        },
        {
          "question": "The Gospel includes",
          "option1": "five books",
          "option2": "one book ",
          "option3": "four books",
          "answer": "four books",
          "full_answer": "The Gospel includes four books: St Matthew, St Mark, St Luke, St John"
        },
        {
          "question": "What does 'testament' mean??",
          "option1": "test",
          "option2": "'covenant' or 'contract'",
          "option3": "taste",
          "answer": "'covenant' or 'contract'",
          "full_answer": "'Testament' means 'covenant' or 'contract'"
        },
        {
          "question": "How many books are included in the Old Testament?",
          "option1": "5",
          "option2": "4 ",
          "option3": "39",
          "answer": "39",
          "full_answer": "There are 39 books included in the Old Testament."
        },
        {
          "question": "'JesusChrist' is mentioned in",
          "option1": "the Old Testament",
          "option2": "the New Testament ",
          "option3": "both",
          "answer": "the New Testament",
          "full_answer": "'JesusChrist' is mentioned in the New Testament"
        },
        {
          "question": "How many books are included in the New Testament?",
          "option1": "27",
          "option2": "39 ",
          "option3": "4",
          "answer": "27",
          "full_answer": "There are included 27 books in the New Testament."
        },
        {
          "question": "In what language was the Old Testament written?",
          "option1": "Middle English",
          "option2": "Latin",
          "option3": "mainly in ancient Hebrew",
          "answer": "mainly in ancient Hebrew",
          "full_answer": "The Old Testament was originally almost entirely written in ancient Hebrew, with a few short elements in Aramaic."
        },
        {
          "question": "In what language was the New Testament written?",
          "option1": "probably in Latin",
          "option2": "probably in Greek ",
          "option3": "probably in ancient Hebrew",
          "answer": "probably in Greek",
          "full_answer": "Probably in Greek, though some may have been first written in Aramaic"
        },
        {
          "question": "When was the first translation of the Bible made into English?",
          "option1": "1600 A.D. by Shakespeare",
          "option2": "1382 A.D. by John Wycliffe ",
          "option3": "both answers are correct",
          "answer": "1382 A.D. by John Wycliffe",
          "full_answer": "The first translation of the Bible was made into English in 1382 A.D. by John Wycliffe."
        },
        {
          "question": "What is the Gutenberg Bible",
          "option1": "the first book ever printed",
          "option2": "the second book ever printed ",
          "option3": "a fancy Bible",
          "answer": "the first book ever printed",
          "full_answer": "The Gutenberg Bible is the first book ever printed (in 1454 A.D. by Johannes Gutenberg who invented the 'typemold' for the printing press.)"
        }
      ],
      "Kings of Israel and Judah": [
        {
          "question": "What does “Bible” mean?",
          "option1": "bibliography",
          "option2": "bubble ",
          "option3": "“books” from Greek",
          "answer": "“books” from Greek",
          "full_answer": "The Bible gets its name from a Greek word meaning “books”."
        },
        {
          "question": "The Bible is sacred to",
          "option1": "the Christian religion",
          "option2": "the Jewish religion ",
          "option3": "both",
          "answer": "both",
          "full_answer": "The Bible is sacred to the Christian and Jewish religion."
        },
        {
          "question": "The Old Testament is also called",
          "option1": "the Old Book",
          "option2": "the Hebrew Bible",
          "option3": "the Magic Book",
          "answer": "the Hebrew Bible",
          "full_answer": "The Old Testament is also called the 'HebrewBible'."
        },
        {
          "question": "What are the three parts of the Old Testament?",
          "option1": "The Pentagon, The Prophets, The Writings",
          "option2": "Genesis, Exodus, Leviticus",
          "option3": "The Pentateuch, The Prophets, The Writings",
          "answer": "The Pentateuch, The Prophets, The Writings",
          "full_answer": "The three parts of the Old Testament are The Pentateuch, The Prophets, The Writings."
        },
        {
          "question": "The Pentateuch includes",
          "option1": "four books",
          "option2": "fifteen books",
          "option3": "five books",
          "answer": "five books",
          "full_answer": "The Pentateuch includes five books: Genesis, Exodus, Leviticus, Numbers, Deuteronomy"
        },
        {
          "question": "The Pentateuch is also called",
          "option1": "The Four Books of Jesus",
          "option2": "The Gospel",
          "option3": "“books” from Greek",
          "answer": "The Five Books of Moses",
          "full_answer": "The Pentateuch is also called The Five Books of Moses"
        },
        {
          "question": "What does 'Gospel' mean?",
          "option1": "'goodnews' from Greek",
          "option2": "gossip ",
          "option3": "Jesus Christ",
          "answer": "'goodnews' from Greek",
          "full_answer": "Gospel means 'goodnews' from Greek."
        },
        {
          "question": "The Gospel includes",
          "option1": "five books",
          "option2": "one book ",
          "option3": "four books",
          "answer": "four books",
          "full_answer": "The Gospel includes four books: St Matthew, St Mark, St Luke, St John"
        },
        {
          "question": "What does 'testament' mean??",
          "option1": "test",
          "option2": "'covenant' or 'contract'",
          "option3": "taste",
          "answer": "'covenant' or 'contract'",
          "full_answer": "'Testament' means 'covenant' or 'contract'"
        },
        {
          "question": "How many books are included in the Old Testament?",
          "option1": "5",
          "option2": "4 ",
          "option3": "39",
          "answer": "39",
          "full_answer": "There are 39 books included in the Old Testament."
        },
        {
          "question": "'JesusChrist' is mentioned in",
          "option1": "the Old Testament",
          "option2": "the New Testament ",
          "option3": "both",
          "answer": "the New Testament",
          "full_answer": "'JesusChrist' is mentioned in the New Testament"
        },
        {
          "question": "How many books are included in the New Testament?",
          "option1": "27",
          "option2": "39 ",
          "option3": "4",
          "answer": "27",
          "full_answer": "There are included 27 books in the New Testament."
        },
        {
          "question": "In what language was the Old Testament written?",
          "option1": "Middle English",
          "option2": "Latin",
          "option3": "mainly in ancient Hebrew",
          "answer": "mainly in ancient Hebrew",
          "full_answer": "The Old Testament was originally almost entirely written in ancient Hebrew, with a few short elements in Aramaic."
        },
        {
          "question": "In what language was the New Testament written?",
          "option1": "probably in Latin",
          "option2": "probably in Greek ",
          "option3": "probably in ancient Hebrew",
          "answer": "probably in Greek",
          "full_answer": "Probably in Greek, though some may have been first written in Aramaic"
        },
        {
          "question": "When was the first translation of the Bible made into English?",
          "option1": "1600 A.D. by Shakespeare",
          "option2": "1382 A.D. by John Wycliffe ",
          "option3": "both answers are correct",
          "answer": "1382 A.D. by John Wycliffe",
          "full_answer": "The first translation of the Bible was made into English in 1382 A.D. by John Wycliffe."
        },
        {
          "question": "What is the Gutenberg Bible",
          "option1": "the first book ever printed",
          "option2": "the second book ever printed ",
          "option3": "a fancy Bible",
          "answer": "the first book ever printed",
          "full_answer": "The Gutenberg Bible is the first book ever printed (in 1454 A.D. by Johannes Gutenberg who invented the 'typemold' for the printing press.)"
        }
      ]
    }
  ]
}